eatrightpro.org 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy

**Updated May 29, 2018**

### SCOPE

This Privacy Policy covers all websites operated by or on behalf of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics and related organizational units. Our websites, or those hosted for us on other platforms, and the purpose of those sites, are listed below (collectively, “Websites”):

  * andhii.org, andeal.org, eal.webauthor.com (research projects, Evidence Analysis Library)
  * cdrnet.org (Commission on Dietetic Registration, home)
  * eatright.org (consumer-focused Website)
  * eatrightfnce.org (conference Website)
  * eatrightfoundation.org (Foundation of the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics)
  * eatrightprep.org (student exam preparation)
  * eatrightpro.org (Academy professionals and practice groups)
  * eatrightstore.org (e-commerce Website)
  * foodandnutrition.org (magazine)
  * ncpro.org (electronic Nutrition Care Process manual)
  * nutritioncaremanual.org (clinical manual)

By accessing and using the Websites you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy. The Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics is committed to maintaining the confidence and trust of our members and other customers and users of the Websites and services. The Academy maintains this Privacy Policy to inform you of the Academy's collection, use and distribution of the personal information you provide online. This Privacy Policy applies to the data collected by us, or those working on our behalf, through information you enter or from the imported data from authorized and approved sources. The Academy may update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time, and we will post a notice of the new Privacy Policy on the Websites. 

### WHAT INFORMATION DOES THE ACADEMY COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?

**Individuals under the Age of 13**  
We do not knowingly collect, solicit or maintain personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register for our services. If you are under 13, please do not send any personal information about yourself (such as your name, address, telephone number, or email address) to us. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete that information from our database. 

If you are a resident of or subject to data privacy laws or regulations of a country outside of the United States, please see the additional provisions at the end of this Privacy Policy (Additional Information for Non United States Residents.)

**Personal Data and/or Personally Identifiable Information (PII)**  
We collect your personal data or PII for various purposes, such as, but not limited to, corresponding with you, informing you about your account, security updates and product information, processing your application, providing you with services, processing your order, providing you with a subscription, or other legitimate purposes. 

“Personal data”, “personally identifiable information” and “PII” are terms that mean information gathered from an individual that can be used (entirely or connected to other information) to distinguish or trace an individual’s identity, such as (but not limited to) name, social security number, address, email address, server ID, date of birth, mother’s maiden name, biometric information, employer name, and telephone number. If you are a resident or citizen of the European Union, please see the applicable provisions toward the end of this Privacy Policy, including the definition of “personal data” that may apply to you.

**From Academy Members, Conference Registrants and Other Customers**  
To gain access to members-only resources and personalization features on the Academy's Websites, members and other users are asked to voluntarily register and/or provide their member login, as well as provide some limited personal information. The Academy asks members to provide their name, member number, business phone and email. Similar information may be submitted to the Academy through membership applications, conference or seminar registration, publication orders, subscriptions and contest registrations. The Academy uses this information to enhance its products and services, and distribution of those products to its members. 

**From E-mail**  
Information sent by email to the Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics is used to process the request or inquiry in the email. 

**E-Commerce**  
Our Websites use forms for users to request information, products and services. We will collect visitor contact information (such as email address) and method of payment. Contact information from the form is used to process orders and to send information about the Academy. User payment information is used to bill the user for products and services. This Website has a secure certificate issued by a certifying agency. The organization has verified the organizational name and that the Academy has the proof of right to use it. This Website legitimately runs under the auspices of the Academy. All information sent to this Website, if in an SSL session, is encrypted. 

**Credit Card Information**  
The Academy collects credit card account information provided by our members and customers to process authorized payments. 

**Surveys**  
Our online surveys ask respondents for contact information (such as email address) and demographic information (such as zip code, age). We also may use data from our surveys to send the user information about our academy. 

**eatright Websites/Membership Registration Forms**  
Our online forms require users to give us contact information (such as name and email address), method of payment and demographic information. We use contact information from the forms to send the user information about our academy. The contact information is also used by the Academy to contact the user from time to time. Information regarding method of payment is collected for member enrollment, registration, to process orders for products and services, and for other uses. 

### HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?

In addition to the above information we use data that we collect about you, or that you provide to us, in the following manner or for the following purposes: 

To process any applications, changes to your account information, or process payments from you (including, but not limited to, membership dues and subscriptions, registration fees, voluntary contributions, examination fees, credential and designation fees, and payments, refunds and reimbursements for any products or services that you choose to purchase from us).  
  
---  
  
To provide you with information on products or services that you request from us.  
  
To provide you with services or process transactions that you have requested.  
  
To communicate with you regarding information, features or offers that we believe will be of interest to you.  
  
To respond to your questions or other requests.   
  
To process other information or personal information that you submit through this Website.  
  
To contact you regarding a contest or promotion in which you have participated.  
  
To present our Website to you. And to notify you about changes to our Websites, our policies, terms or any products or services we offer or provide though it.  
  
To allow you to participate in interactive features on our Websites.  
  
To provide access to restricted parts of our Websites.  
  
To request your participation in surveys, focus groups, or other initiatives which help us to gather information used to develop and enhance our products and services.  
  
To determine eligibility for membership, credentials, designations, or volunteer opportunities.  
  
To evaluate your performance on continued learning courses and assist you in the tracking of your progress.  
  
For examination scheduling, administration and registration purposes.  
  
To serve relevant advertisements to you when you visit our Websites or other third-party sites (including social media platforms).  
  
To enhance and improve our products and services, for example, by performing internal research, analyzing user trends and measuring demographics and interests.  
  
Internal purposes, such as website and system administration or internal audits and reviews.  
  
To comply with applicable law(s) (for example, to comply with a search warrant, subpoena or court order) or to carry out professional ethics/conduct investigations.  
  
For analyzing how the service is used, diagnosing service or technical problems, maintaining security, and personalizing content.  
  
To operate, maintain, and provide to you the features and functionality of the service.  
  
To provide statistics about the usage levels of the Websites and other related information to reputable third parties, but these statistics will not include information which will allow you to be identified.  
  
### HOW DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION?

**Disclosure of Your PII or personal data to Third-Parties**  
Except as provided below, we do not share your information with non-affiliated third parties without your permission. 

We may disclose information you provide via our Websites in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business or a portion of the business of our Websites or any other part of our business, including a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, sale of assets or other corporate change of our direct or indirect parent companies that affects us.

We may need to release PII or personal data when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a criminal investigation, a court order, or legal process served on our Website. We may also share your personal information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of the terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

Service Providers/Trusted Vendors: We also may disclose information to outside companies that help us bring you products and services. For example, we may work with an outside company to: (a) process credit card transactions; (b) manage a database of customer information; (c) assist us in distributing emails; (d) assist us with direct marketing and data collection; (e) provide us storage and analysis; (f) provide fraud prevention; and (g) other services designed to assist us in maximizing our business potential. We require that these outside companies agree to keep confidential all information we share with them and to use the information only to perform their obligations in the agreements.

In addition, the Academy may use your PII or personal data or disclose this information to third parties to contact you about products or services we think may be of interest to you.

**Open Forums**  
Any information you disclose on any electronic mailing list or other open forum hosted by the Academy may be collected by others and used, without authorization by the Academy, to send you unsolicited non-Academy information or for other purposes.

**External Links**  
Any of the Academy Websites may contain links to other external websites that do not fall under the domain of our Websites. The Academy is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such external websites. The Academy does not endorse the content, products or services on other websites. 

**Pop-Up Advertising**  
Some users have reported that advertisements for products, such as diet pills, pop up on their computer screens when they log onto Academy Websites. The Academy has nothing to do with these pop-up ads and does not sanction or control them in any way. 

These ads are triggered by software on the viewer's computer that may have been unwittingly installed as part of a free software package. The most common case is with music and file sharing software that is given away free to consumers. After installation, the software keeps track of the Websites the user logs onto and when the person goes to any site that is on a special list, an ad pops up. Advertisers pay for this and select the sites they want their ads to be associated with.

The Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics does not authorize or approve of this practice and has written to government leaders requesting that legislation be passed to prohibit it.

**Posted Content**  
We may post content on our Websites that you have posted at ours or other websites, e.g., Google (“ **User Content** ”). You agree to and do hereby grant us a royalty-free, sublicensable, transferable, perpetual, irrevocable, non-exclusive, and worldwide right to Use, modify, and perform any User Content we post to our Websites. The term “ **Use** ” includes, but is not limited to, use, reproduce, modify, publish, list information regarding, edit, translate, distribute, publicly display, publicly perform, and make derivative works of the content. 

**Security**  
These Websites have security measures in place designed to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

**Other Uses of Personal Information**  
The Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics also uses PII, including information provided to us from trusted vendors, to continually assess and improve the products and services we offer. To serve you better, we may combine information that you give us on our Websites or via phone, email or mail with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our marketing partners and others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your experience with us, to communicate with you about services and events that may be of interest to you, and for other informational purposes. 

The Academy provides member/customer names and preferred postal addresses (home or work as specified by each individual member/customer) and access to an email deployment (email addresses are never released) to list renters that may be used only for a one-time use mail/email piece approved by (the Academy). Phone numbers and fax numbers are not made available for rental. Email addresses are not released to any third party except contracted service providers who act on behalf of the Academy. The Academy reserves the right to send email communication to Academy members/ customers via email on behalf of a third party, subject to approval by the Academy. Academy members/ customers have the ability to opt out of such mailings and email communications, resulting in such customer's name and address not being included in mailing list rentals and customer's email address being excluded from third party communication.

If you do not wish to receive screened third party offerings via email or postal mail, please email us at [membership@eatright.org](mailto:membership@eatright.org).

### NON-PII or Non-Personal Data

**From General Users**  
As a general matter, Non-Personally Identifiable Information (non-PII) helps us determine how our Website is being used, helps us identify popular areas of the Website and helps determine the effectiveness of our promotional activities regarding the Website. The Academy does not collect any directly personally identifiable information (PII) from users browsing our Websites. Only statistical data — such as the number of hits per page — is collected. This information is used only for internal and marketing purposes and does not include any PII. 

**Cookies and IP Addresses**  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. They provide greater security for Websites that provide personalized information. Cookies are commonly used by websites to provide identification. The cookie you accept is uniquely yours and can be read only by the server that gave it to you. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them. 

A unique number called an IP address identifies every computer on the Internet. Each time you connect to the Internet your machine is assigned an IP address. An IP address is a number that identifies each sender or receiver of information that is sent in packets across the Internet.

You may also turn off cookies in your browser.

### DATA RETENTION

The time periods for which we retain your personal information depend on the purposes for which we use it. We will keep your personal information for as long as your account is active, or as long as you are a registered member or account holder or user of our services or for as long as we have another business purpose to do so and, thereafter, for no longer than is required or permitted by law, or our records retention policy, reasonably necessary for internal reporting and reconciliation purposes, or to provide you with feedback or information you might request. This period of retention is subject to our review and alteration. The information we collect may be stored and processed in servers in the United States and wherever we and our service providers have facilities around the globe.

### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION FOR NON-US RESIDENTS

This Privacy Policy originates and is hosted on a website located in the United States, which has different data protection laws from those of other nations, and particularly member nations in the European Union. Due to differing laws and legal practice, be aware that law enforcement agencies in the United States may have access to your Personal Information.

If you are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from the laws in the United States, please note that we may transfer your information to a country or jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction. It may also be process your information by staff operating outside the EEA who works for us or for one of service providers. If required by applicable law, we will seek your explicit consent to process your Personal Information collected on our Websites or volunteered by you. 

### GDPR

The following provisions apply to you if you are a European citizen or resident. All processing of your personal information is performed in accordance with privacy rights and regulations following the EU Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 (the “Directive”), and the implementations of the Directive in local legislation. As of May 25, 2018, the Directive and local legislation based on the Directive is replaced by the Regulations (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal information and on the free movement of such data, known as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and our processing will take place in accordance with the GDPR. For purposes of the GDPR, we will be the “data controller” of personal information (referred to in the GDPR as “personal data”, and which is defined differently in this Privacy Policy) we collect through the Websites, unless we collect such information on behalf of a “data controller” in which case we will be a “data processor.” This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites, applications or services that do not display or link to this Privacy Policy or that display or link to a different Privacy Policy. For EU residents, to the extent any definition in this Privacy Policy conflicts with a definition under the GDPR, the GDPR definition shall control.

**Your Rights**  
You have the right to have your personal data erased. You have the right to request a copy of your personal data. You have the right to have your personal data we collect corrected. You have the right to object to certain types of processing of your personal data. You can opt-out of certain uses of your personal data. You may request access to your data by sending an email to this address: [manageconsent@eatright.org](mailto:manageconsent@eatright.org). 

**Data Transfers**  
We are headquartered in the United States. As such, we and our service providers may transfer your personal information to, or access it in, jurisdictions that may not provide equivalent levels of data protection as your home jurisdiction. We will take steps to ensure that your personal information receives an adequate level of protection in the jurisdictions in which we process it. If you are located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”) or Switzerland, we provide adequate protection for the transfer of personal information to countries outside of the EEA or Switzerland through a series of intercompany agreements based on the Standard Contractual Clauses. We may also need to transfer your information to other group companies or service providers in countries outside the EEA. This may happen if our servers or suppliers and service providers are based outside the EEA, or if you use our services and products while visiting countries outside this area. 

If you are a resident of country other than the United States, you acknowledge and consent to our collecting, transmitting, and storing your personal information out of the country in which you reside.

**Tell Us What You Think; Contact Information**  
The Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please email [webstrategy@eatright.org](mailto:webstrategy@eatright.org).

An additional privacy statement for the Commission on Dietetic Registration can be found [here](https://www.cdrnet.org/privacy-policy "Go to CDR's privacy policy page.").
